<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Coding Across America</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/feeds/faq.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.codingacrossamerica.com</id><updated>2012-07-28T11:30:11-04:00</updated><entry><title>Frequently Asked Questions</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/faq.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-28T11:30:11-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/faq.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you have a question that's not answered here, please tweet
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/makaimc"&gt;&amp;#64;makaimc&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter with the question and
#camfaq. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="who-are-you"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who are you?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mattmakai.com/about.html"&gt;Matt Makai&lt;/a&gt;, a software
developer living in Washington, DC. I currently focus on Python/Django
development and I've also programmed in Java and Objective-C in the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="where-will-you-stay-during-your-trip"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where will you stay during your trip?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to stay in hotel rooms, use &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.airbnb.com/"&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;
for some cities, and also stay with friends when possible. Some friends
have recommended couch surfing, but I need to look into that more
before I commit to trying it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-are-you-paying-for-all-of-this-travel"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How are you paying for all of this travel?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been saving money for awhile. I'm a strong believer in saving
more than you spend so you have the financial freedom to take on
opportunities such as Coding Across America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also will not have to pay rent for the months I'm away since my lease will
be ending at the same time I begin the trip. As anyone who's lived in the
DC-metro area knows, removing rent eliminates a major financial burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-can-you-learn-about-a-city-in-only-5-10-days"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What can you learn about a city in only 5-10 days?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that remains to be seen. Part of the learning process is planning
the trip, thoroughly researching every city so my time is well spent, and
contacting the right people who know way more than I do about where they
live and then asking them questions. Maybe the answer is that it will only
be superficial knowledge of each destination, but I have a feeling that
more will come of it than just the surface level answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="how-will-you-travel-from-one-city-to-the-next"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How will you travel from one city to the next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be driving in my Black 2004
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honda_S2000"&gt;Honda S2000&lt;/a&gt; with
everything I own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="everything-you-own-in-a-2-seat-sportscar-really"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Everything you own in a 2-seat sportscar? Really?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, almost everything. I'm getting rid of my only piece of furniture (a bed)
and I don't have a TV or desktop computer, so that saves a lot of space.
I'll probably need to keep a box of things at my parents' house though with
items such as my undergrad and graduate school diplomas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-if-this-site-gets-hit-by-slashdot-reddit-etc"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What if this site gets hit by Slashdot, Reddit, etc?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, that would be awesome. There shouldn't be a problem since this site is
static HTML &amp;amp; JavaScript generated with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pelican.readthedocs.org/en/latest/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;. I use Markdown
and the jinja2 templating system to create the pages. The site is hosted
on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, so it &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; scale well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS Thanks Github! Can I visit you guys when I'm in San Francisco?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>