<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Coding Across America</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/feeds/future-post.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.codingacrossamerica.com</id><updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Songs</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/songs.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/songs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlottesville, VA: &amp;quot;Run&amp;quot; by Snow Patrol
Charlotte, NC: &amp;quot;I Can Do Anything&amp;quot; by 3OH!3
Nashville, TN: &amp;quot;Something Like That&amp;quot; by Tim McGraw
Memphis, TN:
New Orleans, LA: &amp;quot;Wide Awake&amp;quot; by Chris Cornell
Austin, TX:
Lubbock, TX:
Los Alamos, NM:
Flagstaff, AZ: &amp;quot;Arizona&amp;quot; by Kings of Leon
San Diego, CA:
Los Angeles, CA:
San Francisco, CA:
Redding, CA:
Eugene, OR:
Portland, OR:
Seattle, WA: &amp;quot;Losing A Whole Year&amp;quot; by Third Eye Blind
Missoula, MT:
Buffalo, WY: &amp;quot;Little Talks&amp;quot; by Of Monsters and Men&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boulder, CO: &amp;quot;Don't Trust Me&amp;quot; by 3OH!3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Des Moines, IA: &amp;quot;Home&amp;quot; by Edward Sharpe and the Magnetic Zeroes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York City, NY:
Morristown, NJ:
Washington, DC: &amp;quot;Amazed&amp;quot; by The Offspring&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Diminishing Marginal Utility of &amp;quot;Stuff&amp;quot;</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/diminishing-marginal-utility-stuff.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/diminishing-marginal-utility-stuff.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found this post on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2012/09/on-the-diminishing-marginal-ut.html"&gt;diminishing marginal utility of stuff&lt;/a&gt;
climbing Hacker News yesterday morning and it resonated with me both in
general and for my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particular lifestyles more easily lend themselves to having less things.
For example, computer programmers without families can live in a cheap
apartment with not much more than a laptop computer, some t-shirts and
jeans. Other professions are not as easy to do with less stuff, such as
working in the financial industry because you tend to need suits, dress
shirts, and ties for both work and social events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet certainly it's much easier today with the digitization of many products
to do with less stuff. I use a Kindle and iPad for reading instead of keeping
mounds of paper books around. I watch movies on-demand instead of storing
a library of DVDs. My pictures are in digital albums instead of physical photo
albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that's not really the point of the post. Really what the author is
getting at is that after a certain point of comfort with food, water,
shelter, and entertainment options, there are less useful things available to
purchase if you are not interested in big-ticket luxury items such as
expensive cars or big houses stocked with furniture. What would really be
worth purchasing is enhancements to ourselves, such as cures for ailments.
The author brings up a vision deficiency he has. Certainly he'd be willing
to pay thousands of dollars to fix that issue but there is no available
cure today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see if advances in biology and bioinformatics
eventually lead to worthwhile purchases that allow people to fix or even
&amp;quot;upgrade&amp;quot; themselves. Wealth would certainly flow from people with means
to the companies that could provide those solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>