<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Coding Across America</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/feeds/post.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/</id><updated>2013-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>New Orleans Entrepreneurship Week</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/new-orleans-entrepreneurship-week.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-03-18:new-orleans-entrepreneurship-week.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="New Orleans' skyline on March 18, 2013" src="../img/130318-new-orleans/morning-skyline.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Orleans' skyline at 630am in the morning the day after my arrival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I arrived in &lt;a class="reference external" href="../new-orleans-la.html"&gt;New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;, Louisana
after a long twelve hour drive down from Charlotte, North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am here participating in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ideavillage.org/"&gt;IdeaVillage&lt;/a&gt;'s
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ideavillage.org/how_it_works/noew/"&gt;New Orleans Entrepreneurship Week&lt;/a&gt;
(NOEW). There are teams of MBA students helping local entrepreneurs work on
their business ideas. I will be assisting the groups, including one this
afternoon. Keynote speakers will give their input throughout the week,
including
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Isaacson"&gt;Walter Isaacson&lt;/a&gt;,
a New Orleans native, who authored the Steve Jobs' biography.
There are also many learning sessions on both technical topics and
entrepreneurial subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My primary goal here is to help out teams from a technical perspective since
the conference often has a dearth of that expertise. I am also talking to
as many New Orleans natives to find out more about their experiences in
entrepreneurship here.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>PyCon</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/hey-pycon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-03-16:hey-pycon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hey PyCon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.excella.com/careers/college-profiles/andrew-baker.aspx"&gt;Andrew Baker&lt;/a&gt;
was awesome enough to present a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mattmakai.com/static/presentations/pycon-andrew-baker.html"&gt;lightning talk&lt;/a&gt;
on Coding Across America this morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a software developer or organization in one of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../cities.html"&gt;thirty cities&lt;/a&gt; I'm planning to visit, please contact me
at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. I'd love to hear from you, either to meet up
or just to find out more about what you love and hate about working in
software in your city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also write feature posts on organizations solving interesting problems with
software. &lt;a class="reference external" href="../human-geo-washington-dc.html"&gt;HumanGeo&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../wisertogether-washington-dc.html"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt; are a couple of
examples. Uppidy, AgilityFeat, and WillowTree Apps will be up in the next
few days once I finish those posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you're a prospective organization and would like to meet, I wrote an FAQ
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../to-prospective-organizations.html"&gt;specifically to answer some of the initial questions&lt;/a&gt;
that might come up on your side. After you read through that, shoot me an
email at &lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. I look forward to hearing from you!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Charlottesville, VA Pictures</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/charlottesville-virginia-day-one-through-five.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-03-14:charlottesville-virginia-day-one-through-five.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are a few &amp;quot;rear of the car&amp;quot;-perspective pictures from the first five
days in Charlottesville. The first several pictures were taken during the
full days I had in Charlottesville when I found an interesting place to
pull over. The final picture was taken in Virginia on the way to Charlotte,
North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my time in Charlottesville I met with Arin Sime of AgilityFeat and
a group from WillowTree Apps. Posts on each company, as well as my thoughts
on working in software development in Washington, DC versus Charlottesville
coming soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Side of the road near Shenandoah Crossing Resort" src="../img/driving-pictures/130310-day-two.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pulled over near &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bluegreenonline.com/explore/resortDetail.aspx?ResortID=4"&gt;Shenandoah Crossing Resort&lt;/a&gt; where I stayed during my time
near Charlottesville.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Entrance to Horton Vineyards" src="../img/driving-pictures/130311-day-three.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entrance to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hortonwine.com/"&gt;Horton Vineyard&lt;/a&gt; in Gordonsville,
Virginia. Sadly I did not have time to stop and drink wine but I thought
their buildings architecture was interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="The Rotunda at the University of Virginia" src="../img/driving-pictures/130312-day-four.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rotunda at the University of Virginia, where I went to grad school
for an
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.commerce.virginia.edu/careerservices/students/Pages/M.S.-in-MIT.aspx"&gt;MS in Management of Information Technology&lt;/a&gt;
('10). I wrote an
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mmakai.com/post/3701139816/uva-masters-in-management-of-information-technology"&gt;in-depth six part blog series&lt;/a&gt;
on the program a few months after I finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Interesting historic marker from the Revolutionary War in Virginia" src="../img/driving-pictures/130313-day-five.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sign marking the history of the area from the Revolutionary War.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Closer view of the historic marker" src="../img/driving-pictures/130313-day-five-2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A closer view of the sign.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>To Prospective Organizations</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/to-prospective-organizations.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-03-10:to-prospective-organizations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;You've received an email from me asking if we can meet at your office or
go out for lunch so that I can tell your story about solving interesting
problems with software. This post attempts to answer some of the initial
questions that may immediately come up on your side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading through this post I am sure you will have further questions.
When you reach that point please email me with those additional questions at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;. I will update this post throughout my trip with
the most frequently asked questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-is-coding-across-america"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What is Coding Across America?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coding Across America is a five month road trip from March until August 2013
to tell stories about people solving problems using software. I am
traveling to thirty cities to meet with people in both large and small
organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="who-have-you-already-met-with"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who Have You Already Met With?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began by writing posts about a few companies in Washington, DC:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="../human-geo-washington-dc.html"&gt;HumanGeo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="../wisertogether-washington-dc.html"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am working on posts for &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.uppidy.com/"&gt;Uppidy&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.agilityfeat.com/"&gt;AgilityFeat&lt;/a&gt; with many more posts within
the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="why-participate"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why Participate?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holding up individuals doing amazing work everywhere in the United States
can inspire others. Most of the technology press focuses on what happens
in Silicon Valley, but there are fascinating stories in every city - yours
included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For about an hour of your time I can gather enough information and
tell your story. It's good press for your organization and your city,
especially as this blog gains momentum as I travel through the thirty
planned destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-questions-are-asked"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Questions Are Asked?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several questions I ask to get the discussion started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the most interesting problems you are solving with software?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the best and worst parts of developing software in your city?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What tech stack are you using? What technologies are you most excited
about working with? What are you moving away from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the greater tech scene in your city help or hurt your
organizations' work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the local and federal governments impact the work you are doing? What
could government do to help you better solve the problems
you are working on, such as rewriting or removing specific regulations?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conversation usually becomes a free discussion towards the end based
on your interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We do not talk about proprietary data. Our discussions are generally on
the detail level of a tech meetup or a conference presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="who-are-you"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Who Are You?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am a developer from Washington, DC. I've been writing on software
development for about three years on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mattmakai.com/"&gt;mattmakai.com&lt;/a&gt; (current) and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mmakai.com/"&gt;mmakai.com&lt;/a&gt; (moved to mattmakai.com).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm hoping my experience as a developer enables me to tell stories from
a unique perspective that a non-technical writer would not be able to provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also have additional answers on my
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../faq.html"&gt;frequently asked questions&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Day One</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/day-one-coding-across-america.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-03-09:day-one-coding-across-america.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;img alt="Driving to Charlottesville, Virginia from Washington, DC" src="../img/driving-pictures/130309-day-one.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A detour on my drive down from Washington, DC to Charlottesville, Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I left Washington, DC to drive to Charlottesville, Virginia. The
drive is about two hours, Route 66 West to 29 South. I managed to fit all
my stuff in my car - barely. Those are my bags piled up on the passenger
seat. I'm getting rid of more of what I own so everything can fit in my
trunk. Some of it I can pitch naturally; there are few clothes I know I
can get rid of as well as some random items to toss. Still, that trunk
is &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>WiserTogether</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/wisertogether-washington-dc.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-03-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-03-01:wisertogether-washington-dc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;How do people facing life-altering health care decisions make the right
choices for their treatment? People turn to family, friends, and the web
to obtain advice outside of the doctor's office. However, information
available through these channels often creates more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, Shub Debgupta and his wife faced a nightmare scenario
during the pregancy of their first child. They were told their child could
be born with significant learning difficulties. Shub and his
wife asked themselves questions they could not find answers to, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How did other people handle their situation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would doctors, themselves faced with such a situation, choose to do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How should they weight myriad factors important to their decision?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shub and his wife were fortunate. Their child was born healthy, without the
complications they feared. Yet this agnonizing experience stuck with Shub. In
early 2008, he founded &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wisertogether.com/"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt;
to improve health care decision making for patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="WiserTogether's logo at their offices in Georgetown, Washington, DC" src="../img/130227-wisertogether/wisertogether-logo.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shub's vision created a &amp;quot;learn, compare, connect, then decide&amp;quot; process
aided by actual patient data collected continuously since the company's
foundeding five years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process and data combine as the platform
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://mywiserhealth.com/"&gt;WiserHealth&lt;/a&gt;. WiserHealth is a suite of
products for patients with varying situations, including pregnancy, arthritis,
heart problems, depression, diabetes, and respiratory diseases. The products
are sold to organizations that offer one or more of WiserHealth's services
to its employees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="wiserhealth-development-in-washington-dc"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;WiserHealth Development in Washington, DC&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WiserTogether's main office is in Georgetown, Washington, DC, just off
the classic M Street drag. Some employees also work remotely across the
United States in California and Georgia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://goo.gl/maps/sNcMm"&gt;&lt;img alt="WiserTogether's main office location" src="../img/130227-wisertogether/wisertogether-georgetown-office-location.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met with several members of WiserTogether's development team, including
their Chief Technology Officer &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://twitter.com/easel"&gt;Erik LaBianca&lt;/a&gt;.
WiserTogether uses a range of current technologies including
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;,
and a combination of client-side HyperText Markup Language (HTML),
JavaScript, and Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) to deliver the WiserHealth
platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="a picture of WiserTogether's office in Georgetown, Washington, DC" src="../img/130227-wisertogether/wisertogether-offices.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team currently releases software updates two to three times a week and
is moving towards daily updates. Eventually they hope to have a
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continuous_delivery"&gt;continuous delivery&lt;/a&gt;
model in place for continuous updates certified with an extensive
automated testing suite before being released to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Lunch with several of WiserTogether's development team" src="../img/130227-wisertogether/wisertogether-development-team.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lunch at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thunderburger.com/index1.html"&gt;Thunderburger&lt;/a&gt; with
several members of WiserTogether's development team. From left to right, Erik,
Kamalesh, Johnny, Jimmy, and Tareque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the topics we discussed was how software development is impacted by
being located in Washington, DC. Several development team members commented
that the technology meetup scene far surpasses some other
cities they've worked in. Washington, DC has well established
groups such as &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://dcpython.org/"&gt;DC Python&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.django-district.org/"&gt;Django District&lt;/a&gt; that attract
fifty-plus developers to monthly meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a major disadvantage to working in software development in the
District is the shadow of the Federal government. Government agencies and
the military throw large sums of money around to &amp;quot;solve&amp;quot; problems.
Investments are not ramped up gradually based on project success but
are dumped all at once within a single fiscal year. This approach is
a complete mismatch with how to develop quality software. Instead, a
small software project using limited resources should prove that a
real problem is being solved.  Only then, if the solution proves
successful based on user feedback, should funding gradually increase to
build expanded features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two additional major issues arise from the amount of money that
is invested in large software projects for federal agencies. First, these
projects drain the local talent pool and increase developer salaries for
competing non-government technology companies. Second, the excessive
money leads to complicated, overengineered systems with vast arrays of
features that are wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-can-government-do-to-help"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Can Government Do To Help?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can federal and state governments help companies like
WiserTogether so they can improve the health care quality in the United
States? Our discussion coalesced around three aspects where government
must improve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clarify &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Health_Insurance_Portability_and_Accountability_Act"&gt;HIPAA&lt;/a&gt; laws by making regulations testable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly declare platforms that are pre-audited and approved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an open
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nih.gov/"&gt;National Institutes of Health&lt;/a&gt; (NIH) ontology
application programming interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clarifying HIPAA was a central theme during our discussion. The laws are
so convoluted that no one except lawyers can interpret the regulations.
Audits by the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hhs.gov/"&gt;Department of Health and Human Services&lt;/a&gt;
(DHHS) are a nightmare. Fortunately, WiserTogether has not been been audited
directly by DHHS, but other organizations they work with have been.
Auditors are looking for a reason to &amp;quot;prove&amp;quot; their own worth by finding
fault with something. This is a broken system that both prevents innovative
companies from complying with the law (because no one can interpret it
properly) and creates a powerful disincentive to not start a company that
has to comply with these regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another issue is the need to clarify which platforms are
HIPAA-compliant for audit purposes. For example, the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.heroku.com/"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; platform-as-a-service could provide
a great foundation for health care applications. Unfortunately, no one knows
whether Heroku would pass an audit by Department of Health and Human Services.
Heroku is not a niche service - it is owned by Salesforce and runs millions
of applications for thousands of companies around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik and his team also recommended that the National
Institute of Health should create an open ontology open application
programming interface (API). Companies in the healthcare industry could use
the API to organize data in their applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am certainly no expert in the health care industry and I could be wrong
about the above points. If I am, please email me at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="mailto:matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com"&gt;matthew.makai&amp;#64;gmail.com&lt;/a&gt; so I can correct my misinterpretations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-s-next"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 9, I will head out to Charlottesville, Virginia and begin my tour
of 30 cities across the United States. I may meet with and write about one
or two more companies in DC before heading out if I can fit it into next
week's schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you enjoyed WiserTogether's story, you may also enjoy reading about
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../human-geo-washington-dc.html"&gt;HumanGeo's approach to product development&lt;/a&gt;
for geospatial mapping software in the cleared intelligence space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Schedule Curveball</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/schedule-curveball.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-02-26:schedule-curveball.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My schedule is shifting slightly before I hit the road in less than two
weeks. I have an opportunity to observe and assist at
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ideavillage.org/"&gt;IdeaVillage&lt;/a&gt;'s
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://ideavillage.org/how_it_works/noew/"&gt;New Orleans Entrepreneurship Week&lt;/a&gt; (NOEW)
from March 16th through the 22nd. That is a week earlier than I planned to
be in New Orleans. I do not want to pass up this great opportunity to
showcase what's going on in New Orleans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To attend NOEW I am forced to drop Nashville. I will drive directly from
Charlotte to New Orleans. After New Orleans I will backtrack north to
Memphis for a few days. Then I will head through Dallas to Austin where
the remainder of my schedule is the same. The dates on my
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../cities.html"&gt;cities&lt;/a&gt; page have been updated with this schedule change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I have booked my accomodations in
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../charlottesville-va.html"&gt;Charlottesville&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../charlotte-nc.html"&gt;Charlotte&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../new-orleans-la.html"&gt;New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="../memphis-tn.html"&gt;Memphis&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../las-vegas-nv.html"&gt;Las Vegas&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../los-angeles-ca.html"&gt;Los Angeles&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../san-francisco-ca.html"&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the next few days I will book &lt;a class="reference external" href="../dallas-tx.html"&gt;Dallas&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../austin-tx.html"&gt;Austin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="../lubbock-tx.html"&gt;Lubbock&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../los-alamos-nm.html"&gt;Los Alamos&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="../moab-ut.html"&gt;Moab&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../flagstaff-az.html"&gt;Flagstaff&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a class="reference external" href="../san-diego-ca.html"&gt;San Diego&lt;/a&gt;.
I want to keep my schedule somewhat flexible after that period of time so I
will hold off on booking anything after San Francisco for at least a couple
of weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My story on &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wisertogether.com/"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt; is up next.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>HumanGeo</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/human-geo-washington-dc.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-02-20:human-geo-washington-dc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Is there a better model for building certain types of software products
used by the federal government? With billions of dollars* in
failed information technology projects over the last decade, there certainly
seems to be room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the issues with products built for government workers is that
commonly users who will actually work with the system do not control how
money is spent. Managers who will not be using the system are wowed by
great demos and flashy features. Yet many of those features are useless
to the real users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="HumanGeo's logo as seen from their office" src="../img/130220-human-geo/human-geo-logo.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thehumangeo.com/"&gt;HumanGeo&lt;/a&gt;
(&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/thehumangeo"&gt;&amp;#64;thehumangeo&lt;/a&gt;),
based in Arlington, Virginia across the Potomac River from Washington,
DC, appears to have a better model. Experts in military intelligence at
HumanGeo work directly with their top notch software developers. Together
they create elegant solutions to hard problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external image-reference" href="http://goo.gl/maps/skkC2"&gt;&lt;img alt="HumanGeo's Arlington office location" src="../img/130220-human-geo/human-geo-arlington-office-location.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers are granted freedom to use powerful technologies such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://d3js.org/"&gt;d3.js&lt;/a&gt; for
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mbostock.github.com/d3/talk/20111018/collision.html"&gt;dynamic&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://bl.ocks.org/mbostock/4063570"&gt;visualization&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mbostock.github.com/d3/talk/20111116/force-collapsible.html"&gt;creation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://leafletjs.com/"&gt;Leaflet&lt;/a&gt; for cross-platform (both dekstop
and mobile), interactive maps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hbase.apache.org/"&gt;HBase&lt;/a&gt; for storing and accessing massive
amounts of data that can be feed into algorithms to create actionable
information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These free &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software"&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;
software libraries are commonly used by start ups and organizations with
effective software development embedded in their culture. However, the above
technologies (among many others) are rarely used in government projects.
Government employees and contractors are often hamstrung by a rigid set of
pre-approved technologies that cannot solve problems in effective ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the only tool available to you is a hammer, everything looks
like a nail.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rigid toolset is indicative of larger organization dysfunction. When
the software development process does not work, well-meaning but
non-technical supervisors add more procedures and checkpoints. The
organization becomes content with failing in a structured way instead of
succeeding with a flexible approach to software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="change-the-approach"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Change the Approach&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HumanGeo's approach to solving problems in the intelligence space breaks
down barriers between real system users and software developers. Feedback
is immediate and clear. Relationships and trust are built between the experts
who understand their fields and developers who understand a wide swath of
technologies. Once a product solves a problem, HumanGeo's well-respected
intelligence analysts influence others in their community facing
that problem. HumanGeo sells their products and consulting services
around effective solutions to real issues faced by users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HumanGeo's approach is not perfect, but it is a marked departure from
how many large firms in the Washington, DC region operate. Traditionally,
large federal government consulting firms sell a &amp;quot;butts in seats&amp;quot; model. Get
contractors in the door and let them augment staff positions.
Developers have limited freedom and influence to change the status quo.
They are contracted to do as they are told even if that direction is a clear
path to failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of HumanGeo's developers came from other DC consulting firms who
follow the butts-in-seats model; some are my former coworkers. We saw
first hand how we were shipped off to a government site and put in a seat.
We railed against the inefficiencies from the inside without
understanding the dynamic that it was in the best interest of our
employer to maintain the failing status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="figure"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Clint and Mike from HumanGeo" src="../img/130220-human-geo/clint-and-mike.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Clint and Mike, two developers at HumanGeo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers at HumanGeo are constantly experimenting with new technologies
and sharing that knowledge among members of the team. They also reach out
to the greater community through technology meetups such as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.meetup.com/Intel-Analytics-DC/"&gt;Intel Analytics DC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="government-as-a-platform"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Government as a Platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked HumanGeo's developers about
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../tim-oreilly-open-government.html"&gt;Tim O'Reilly's ideas on government as a platform&lt;/a&gt;. They agreed having more raw data available through
APIs would help private industry create new applications for citizens.
In the military intelligence space there would need to be limits on
access. Yet many principles of data sharing from citizen-facing agencies can
make the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_clearance"&gt;security cleared&lt;/a&gt;
sector more effective as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting idea emerged from our discussion: how do you get
large public datasets from the government onto platforms where innovative
applications can be created? Downloading large data sets can take hours or
days and then it often needs to be uploaded into another environment. Large
data transfers incur a bandwidth cost that is often prohibitively expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One idea is for the government to partner with cloud services such as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://aws.amazon.com/"&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://openshift.redhat.com/app/"&gt;Red Hat OpenShift&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.rackspace.com/cloud/"&gt;Rackspace Cloud&lt;/a&gt; to offer lower cost
access to public data on platforms that developers can immediately use to
do heavy data processing. With the data already on the platform data it would
not require immediate transfer to become useful. It's an idea worth further
exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="what-s-next"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What's Next?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I interviewed a development team from a Washington, DC company
with a platform for making informed decisions about many aspects of personal
healthcare. My story about
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wisertogether.com/"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt; comes next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="references"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;*References&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.washingtonpost.com/wp-dyn/content/article/2006/08/17/AR2006081701485.html"&gt;FBI Virtual Case Management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Air_traffic_control#Technology"&gt;FAA air traffic control software projects&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ndia.org/Divisions/Divisions/SystemsEngineering/Documents/Studies/NDIA%20Top%20SW%20Issues%202010%20Report%20v5a%20final.pdf"&gt;DoD software development issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Tim O'Reilly on Open Government</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/tim-oreilly-open-government.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-02-19:tim-oreilly-open-government.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/timoreilly"&gt;Tim O'Reilly&lt;/a&gt; came to the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.consumerfinance.gov/"&gt;Consumer Financial Protection Bureau&lt;/a&gt;
(CFPB) on Thursday, February 14th. Tim discussed a range
of topics centered on open government and transparency. I attended Tim's talk
as part of the greater Technology &amp;amp; Innovation team although he
primarily came to talk with our new
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.consumerfinance.gov/jobs/design-technology-fellows/"&gt;design and technology fellows&lt;/a&gt;.
I thought it would be interesting to share his ideas with a wider audience.
I've grouped the topics together in this post around the ideas - the
ordering here is not necessarily how the discussion was structured. There
were a lot of questions that directed the conversation. Any errors and
omissions are mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="CFPB logo outside the building" src="../img/130219-tim-oreilly-cfpb/cfpb_logo.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="government-as-a-platform"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Government as a Platform&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US government can often create the greatest public benefit by building
platforms that citizens and the private sector can extend. A widely-known
example is
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_Positioning_System"&gt;GPS&lt;/a&gt;.
GPS was initially built by the military and then later opened for public use.
The applications that are now possible for navigation and positioning would
not have been possible if the military alone created the end user
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source is a key part of government as a platform. Luckily CFPB has
already &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://github.com/cfpb"&gt;open sourced&lt;/a&gt; applications on Github.
The agency is hoping to open source even more software, particularly the
internal communication and collaboration tools we've built over the past
couple of years. I developed many of those projects so if they are open
sourced I'll be sure to write posts about the best ways to build on top
of them (they are written in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.djangoproject.com/"&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Tim O'Reilly speaking in the auditorium in Washington, DC" src="../img/130219-tim-oreilly-cfpb/tim_oreilly.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="serve-and-create-heroes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Serve and Create Heroes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim exhorted the Fellows and other CFPB public servants to always remember
to &lt;em&gt;serve the People&lt;/em&gt;. Sometimes we get caught up in daily tasks and petty
inter office politics. Always take a step back and realize we serve a greater
purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CFPB should broadcast achievements as the agency executes its mission. Hold
people up as examples and heroes so others want to be like them. The public
needs to know and understand that great work is being done in many parts of
the government. Stories about individuals that are relatable and memorable
bridge the gap between nameless, faceless agencies and the public servants
who work hard to achieve an agency's mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-next-big-thing"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The &amp;quot;Next Big Thing&amp;quot;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the CFPB fellows asked &amp;quot;what's the next big thing&amp;quot; along the lines
of Web 2.0. Tim explained that there is never just one major thing.
Generally several novel or materially improved technologies combine to
create &amp;quot;the next big thing.&amp;quot; Today, the two technologies on the horizon
that have the potential for great change are pervasive sensor networks
and new techniques for large scale data analysis - &amp;quot;big data&amp;quot; is the term
being thrown around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example of how sensors, data, and large scale analysis combine came
from Tim's discussion with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://norvig.com/bio.html"&gt;Peter Norvig&lt;/a&gt;
at Google. Peter described Google's self-driving cars as a triumph of memory,
not algorithms. The process of mapping the roads for Google Maps allowed
large scale data collection that could be analyzed. The outcome of that
analysis (which is ongoing, not a discrete one-time process)
combined with brilliant engineering leads to capabilities for autonomous
vehicles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="legislation-and-technology"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Legislation and Technology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tim discussed how technologists have an opportunity to get &lt;em&gt;ahead&lt;/em&gt; of policy
makers. We in the software development community have a responsibility to
show how technology can be used for good. We also must warning against the
dangers that can arise from misuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find topics of government as a platform and what the government can do
to encourage technology entrepreneurship fascinating. These are major themes
for this blog over the next five months as I travel to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../cities.html"&gt;30 cities around the United States&lt;/a&gt; and interview other
developers. Within the next day I'll have Friday's interview with
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thehumangeo.com/company.php"&gt;HumanGeo&lt;/a&gt; posted. Next up is
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wisertogether.com/"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>(Less Than) One Month to Go</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/less-than-one-month-to-go.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-02-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-02-14:less-than-one-month-to-go.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Now things get interesting. There are only twenty two days remaining until
I hit the road on March 9th. In the next few days I will publish a post about
Tim O'Reilly's fascinating talk about open government yesterday at one
of my clients - the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB). Tim
discussed a range of topics, including how CFPB can continue to set an
example for transparency and openness in government.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At 430 I meet with &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.thehumangeo.com/company.php"&gt;HumanGeo&lt;/a&gt;
at their office in Arlington, Virginia. HumanGeo's consultants specialize
in creating geospatial visualizations and develop software with Python.
Really sharp guys doing interesting software development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week is &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wisertogether.com/"&gt;WiserTogether&lt;/a&gt; in Georgetown.
Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>DC Python Group Coding</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/dc-python-group-coding.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-01-26:dc-python-group-coding.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Washington, DC is most commonly associated with politics but it has
quite a technology scene as well. I'm taking advantage of as many of the
events I can attend before hitting the road in March. Today is DC Python's
group coding session at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.socialcode.com/"&gt;SocialCode&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developers are working on projects such as scientific and numeric analysis
with NumPy and SciPy, geographic information systems, a Jenkins-based
software-as-a-service platform that runs off Amazon Web Services, new
Python commandline tools, and some
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.pygame.org/news.html"&gt;PyGame&lt;/a&gt; projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did writing on the web frameworks section of
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.fullstackpython.com/"&gt;Full Stack Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some pictures from the event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img alt="Group hacking on Jenkins project" src="../img/130126-dc-python-coding/group_hacking.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Group hacking on a Jenkins software-as-a-service project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Whiteboarding the Jenkins project" src="../img/130126-dc-python-coding/whiteboard.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whiteboarding the Jenkins project user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Working with NumPy and SciPy" src="../img/130126-dc-python-coding/group_hacking2.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups discussing their projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Working with NumPy and SciPy" src="../img/130126-dc-python-coding/documentation_onscreen.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Displaying and discussing documentation for scientific and data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Josh and Ryan in the kitchen area of SocialCode's office" src="../img/130126-dc-python-coding/josh_and_ryan.jpg" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Josh and Ryan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ryanday.net/"&gt;Ryan Day&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/j00bar"&gt;Josh Ginsberg&lt;/a&gt; and SocialCode for organizing the event and providing us
with an awesome space for the day.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Comments</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/comments.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-01-25:comments.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; got around to adding a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://disqus.com/"&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt;-based
comments system to this site. Currently all blog posts and the city
research pages have an area for comments at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The comment system needs to be tweaked. I'll probably modify it to
allow anonymous posts. There are probably other settings I can change
that will be beneficial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Head over to the &lt;a class="reference external" href="../cities.html"&gt;cities&lt;/a&gt; page, pick a city, and write
up recommendations for what I should do and see while I'm there on my
trip.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Wikivoyage and a Bonus City</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/wikivoyage-and-bonus-city.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-01-16:wikivoyage-and-bonus-city.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just found out about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikivoyage.org/wiki/Main_Page"&gt;Wikivoyage&lt;/a&gt; today. I can't believe I did not know about it earlier. Wikivoyage is
Wikipedia for destinations. I will use Wikivoyage extensively for this trip
as it complements my &lt;a class="reference external" href="../cities.html"&gt;cities&lt;/a&gt; pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a bonus city for this trip in April: Las Vegas. I am going to
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.microconf.com/"&gt;Microconf&lt;/a&gt; 2013 from April 28 through April 30.
I'll probably spend one extra day checking out Vegas before heading off to
Los Angeles. I'll also be at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://max.adobe.com/"&gt;Adobe MAX&lt;/a&gt; the
weekend following Microconf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also looking at attending &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://uxmad.com/"&gt;UXMad&lt;/a&gt; while in Madison,
Wisconsin. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://lanyrd.com/"&gt;Lanyrd&lt;/a&gt; is a godsend for finding these
types of events.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Two Months To Go</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/two-months-to-go.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-01-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2013-01-09:two-months-to-go.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With exactly two months until I hit the road my focus has now shifted to
finishing my research on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="../cities.html"&gt;cities I'll be visiting&lt;/a&gt; and
communicating with tech groups and companies and I'll be meeting on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm in the process of booking the hotels for the first ten cities I'll
be in - that should take me through sometime in April. I'll book later
destinations once I'm on the road so I can have more flexibility to
move dates around based on interesting events. For example, the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://max.adobe.com/"&gt;Adobe MAX&lt;/a&gt; looks great even though it was a
few days off from when I was planning to be in LA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a side note, this article in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.wired.com/wiredenterprise/2013/01/hack-the-government/"&gt;Wired on 'How to Hack the Government&lt;/a&gt;
is pretty interesting. I currently develop software for CFPB (one of
my clients) and it's great to see Github and open source getting good
press. Hopefully other areas of the government follow suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The often antiquated software development practices other agencies use need a
serious upgrade so the government can stop spending so much damn money on
technology and getting so little for it. There's a whole host of other
government problems that would need to be addressed outside what this
article discusses but it's an interesting start nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Redding, CA?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-redding-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-12-26:why-redding-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Redding is a small town of about 90k residents in Northern California,
about three and a half hours from San Francisco. From my initial research
there doesn't seem to be much of a technology start up scene here. That's
fine - this is another destination where I can spend some time programming
and writing without interruptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redding looks like a beautiful city (I've never been there before) and I'll
need a break after the gauntlet of San Diego-LA-San Francisco. Redding and
Eugene, Oregon provide a week respite before diving back into the startup
scenes of Portland and Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Sundial bridge in Redding, California" src="../img/redding-ca-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../redding-ca.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Redding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dandeluca/3697142049/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Convictions</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/convictions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-11-26:convictions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;quot;Some convictions are so strong that the world must break to
accommodate them.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly hold two convictions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software development is awesome - if you're stressed out and not
delivering amazing new work to end users every day, you're doing it wrong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More young people need to be inspired to go into software development
by &lt;em&gt;showing&lt;/em&gt; them how amazing the work is&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that's a huge part of what my trip is about. Software development isn't
about geeks sitting behind monitors in a dark room all day. It's not about
people that can't socialize with others so they are relegated to a corner
with a computer. It's not about &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.cnn.com/2012/05/07/tech/web/brogrammers/index.html"&gt;brogrammers&lt;/a&gt; (don't even get me started on that
shit).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software development is about solving problems using technology. You
can only solve problems that truly matter if you talk to people
&lt;em&gt;with problems&lt;/em&gt;. And that's part of why I'm traveling across the United States
for 5 months - to prove that software development is more than just the
stereotypical geek sitting behind a computer every minute of the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If more people are inspired to do great work in technology then this
trip will be worth it for more than just myself and the world will be better
off for it.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Research</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/research.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-11-21:research.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have not posted on this blog in a few weeks but work continues on
researching my thirty destinations. I constantly add potential tech
companies to their respective city pages as well as meet up groups and
interesting spots to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already have a great group of both large and small tech companies with
confirmed visit dates in various cities. Once I get a little closer to my
launch date on March 9, I'll post the companies and the times I will be
visiting their offices. Having a known set of dates I will
be in each city really helps with confirming office visits as well as
meet ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also on my to do list is getting comments put on each city page and blog
post. It's easy to implement but I haven't gotten around to it. Random
other projects have taken precedence such as my quick one weekend web app
side project
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.visualizationportfolio.com/"&gt;Visualization Portfolio&lt;/a&gt;,
working with my consulting firm on potential new Python clients, and knocking
out great work at my current clients before I hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now is about the time when things come together as my research fills in
most of my destinations, I book accomodations in more cities, and I confirm
with even more companies about visiting and talking to them about what they
love (and don't love) about working in technology in their city. Much more
to come soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>30 in 5</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/30-in-5.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-30:30-in-5.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The schedule is now set. Thirty cities in just over five months (exactly
five months and six days). March 9, 2013 to August 15, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final city additions include Detroit, Buffalo (NY), and Boston while I
cut Pittsburgh and Indianapolis since they took me too far south to visit
Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am currently finishing up my research on each city and planning
individual days when I will be programming, meeting up with people, and
exploring each city. I won't have every day planned exactly - it's better
to leave some flexibility in case there are unexpected adventures along
the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details to come soon now that it's about four months until the trip
begins.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why San Francisco, CA?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-san-francisco-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-24:why-san-francisco-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why not San Francisco? Technically this stop is a combination of
the areas in and around San Francisco, Palo Alto, and San Jose. There are
so many interesting start ups, venture capital firms, and technology
meetups it's difficult to know where to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've never been to San Francisco (or CA before this trip). These will
be ten very busy days talking to companies, other software developers,
and going to tech meetups, as well as exploring the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="San Francisco skyline at dusk" src="../img/san-francisco-ca-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where do I begin? I want to visit both well-known technology companies
such as Facebook and Github as well as smaller companies that are not
yet tech mainstream names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../san-francisco-ca.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/fritography/4523813603/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Los Angeles, CA?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-los-angeles-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-21:why-los-angeles-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have never been to Los Angeles before. The stories I hear about LA's
massive traffic jams and major suburban sprawl remind me of Northern
Virginia - only worse. A trip up the West Coast just wouldn't seem complete
though without a stop in LA. And it'll a comparison point for what I see
in San Diego, San Francisco, and Seattle's start up scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Los Angeles is stop number twelve out of the thirty cities I am visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Los Angeles at night from Griffith Observatory" src="../img/los-angeles-ca-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the &lt;a class="reference external" href="https://twitter.com/LA_Startups"&gt;Los Angeles Startups twitter account&lt;/a&gt; really useful for learning about companies in the city. There are
many small companies here which is expected for a city with almost 13 million
people in the metro area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I'll find interesting is whether being close to San Francisco helps
or hurts entrepreneurship. On one hand, I'm sure
some people move back and forth between California cities which helps
spread ideas about technology and innovation. On the other hand, if you're
serious about starting a company, maybe people just up and move to San
Francisco / Palo Alto. Perhaps a third variable, such as the major
prescence of the movie industry, impacts the startup landscape in a
more dramatic way than proximity to other California cities. This situation
needs more research before I take off on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../los-angeles-ca.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/39214918&amp;#64;N03/4451675186/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why San Diego, CA?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-san-diego-ca.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-13:why-san-diego-ca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;San Diego was a late addition to my slate of destinations. I added San Diego
for a couple of reasons. First, I ran into an old friend in DC who was
back in town visiting from San Diego. She loves living in San Diego,
asked me &amp;quot;why not visit?&amp;quot; and I didn't have a good answer for why I
wasn't going. So that got me started thinking about it. Second, my
brother hung out in San Diego for a few days when he drove across the
country and he said it was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus no trip up the West Coast would seem complete unless I went the almost
full length from San Diego to Seattle. San Diego is destination number
eleven during Coding Across America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Port of San Diego with the city in the background" src="../img/san-diego-ca-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where my Coding Across America trip puts the focus back on technology,
meet ups, and start ups. San Diego has a pretty good tech scene. There's quite
a &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.xconomy.com/san-diego/2012/07/20/san-diego-startups-raise-over-300m-from-vcs-in-second-quarter/"&gt;bit of venture funding here&lt;/a&gt;
and more start ups than I have time to talk with. This should be an exciting
location to visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../san-diego-ca.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about San Diego.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/portofsandiego/5495014146/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Flagstaff, AZ?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-flagstaff-az.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-10:why-flagstaff-az.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Flagstaff is the last stop in the leg of my trip that is primarily composed
of small towns and beautiful outside scenery. This is destination number ten during
Coding Across America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why Flagstaff instead of Phoenix, which is only a couple hours further South? No particular
reason. Having four stops in a row that will be pretty small towns before hitting the
San Diego-Los Angeles-San Francisco West Coast corridor will be an interesting contrast
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Lake Mary in Flagstaff, Arizona" src="../img/flagstaff-az-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lake Mary in Flagstaff, Arizona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The University of Northern Arizona has its
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.nacet.org/"&gt;Center for Entrepreneurship and Technology&lt;/a&gt;. So there's some
signs of life here. I'll be on the look out over the next couple of months for small
start ups and companies that are located around here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../flagstaff-az.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Flagstaff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/91393778&amp;#64;N00/3038533783/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Moab, Utah?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-moab-ut.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-07:why-moab-ut.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently added Moab to my list of destinations after a couple of
recommendations from people I randomly met. Moab looks amazing from photos
but apparently none of them do it justice. &amp;quot;You have to see it in person&amp;quot;
I'm told. So with that Moab will be destination number nine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I expect that this will be the third stop in the leg of my trip that takes
me out of the tech scene and lets me focus primarily on developing my own
software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Canyon Lands National Park - Moab, Utah" src="../img/moab-ut-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlikely there's anything. I'm mainly here to take in the sights and hike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../moab-ut.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Moab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/dfb_photos/6193076965/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Los Alamos, New Mexico?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-los-alamos-nm.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-10-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-10-06:why-los-alamos-nm.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Los Alamos, New Mexico is another one of those destinations that leaves
people wondering &amp;quot;what does that have to do with tech&amp;quot;? It is definitely
not a town that people associate with startups like Palo Alto, Seattle,
Boulder, or Austin. Still there is a lot of advanced research going on here
although it's not well publicized outside of academic circles. Some of the
work is classified as well. Despite my Top Secret security clearance,
I'm unfortunately not going to get to see the cool classified work going
on in
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Los_Alamos_National_Laboratory"&gt;Los Alamos National Laboratory&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's likely most of my time here will be spent outdoors or in small town
getting some solid coding time in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Sky Crane burns behind Los Alamos, New Mexico" src="../img/los-alamos-nm-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sky Crane burns behind Los Alamos, New Mexico's airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../los-alamos-nm.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Los Alamos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ethanfrogget/5968569467/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Lubbock, Texas?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-lubbock-tx.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-27:why-lubbock-tx.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lubbock is home to the Red Raiders of Texas Tech University and is about
seven hours Northwest of Austin, Texas. Lubbock will be the seventh city
I visit during Coding Across America. This stop begins the leg of my trip
that will take me to some remote place in the Southwest United States,
including Los Alamos, Moab, and Flagstaff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be difficult to find technology-related ventures in Lubbock outside of
Texas Tech University. An Indeed.com search for Django and Ruby on Rails
turned up... nothing. Ditto for tech meetups. But in lieu of other software
developers to talk to, I'm looking forward to spending some time here in
an area of the United States I would otherwise be unlikely to visit. It's
also a great excuse to get plenty of time for heads-down coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Just South of Lubbock, TX" src="../img/lubbock-tx-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much here from what I can find. I'll have to do further digging to see
if Texas Tech University sponsors any type of incubator or entrepreurship
classes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../lubbock-tx.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Lubbock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/imagesbywestfall/3423388821/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Diminishing Marginal Utility of "Stuff"</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/diminishing-marginal-utility-stuff.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-23:diminishing-marginal-utility-stuff.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I found this post on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.antipope.org/charlie/blog-static/2012/09/on-the-diminishing-marginal-ut.html"&gt;diminishing marginal utility of stuff&lt;/a&gt;
climbing Hacker News yesterday morning and it resonated with me both in
general and for my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particular lifestyles more easily lend themselves to having less things.
For example, computer programmers without families can live in a cheap
apartment with not much more than a laptop computer, some t-shirts and
jeans. Other professions are not as easy to do with less stuff, such as
working in the financial industry because you tend to need suits, dress
shirts, and ties for both work and social events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet certainly it's much easier today with the digitization of many products
to do with less stuff. I use a Kindle and iPad for reading instead of keeping
mounds of paper books around. I watch movies on-demand instead of storing
a library of DVDs. My pictures are in digital albums instead of physical photo
albums.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that's not really the point of the post. Really what the author is
getting at is that after a certain point of comfort with food, water,
shelter, and entertainment options, there are less useful things available to
purchase if you are not interested in big-ticket luxury items such as
expensive cars or big houses stocked with furniture. What would really be
worth purchasing is enhancements to ourselves, such as cures for ailments.
The author brings up a vision deficiency he has. Certainly he'd be willing
to pay thousands of dollars to fix that issue but there is no available
cure today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see if advances in biology and bioinformatics
eventually lead to worthwhile purchases that allow people to fix or even
&amp;quot;upgrade&amp;quot; themselves. Wealth would certainly flow from people with means
to the companies that could provide those solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Austin, Texas?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-austin-tx.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-22:why-austin-tx.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Austin was the first city I put on the map during my road trip planning.
I knew there was no way I was going to skip it or just spend a couple of days
there. Nothing less than a full week will suffice. In fact, much of my early
planning and building of this website was done while visiting Austin for a
week in June 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've been to Austin three times previously. Every time has been amazing and
in different ways. There's something about the friendly culture, somewhat
liberal attitude mixed with hipster weirdness and technology start ups that
I find tremendously appealing. Plus Austin has some of the best bars anywhere
with 4th &amp;amp; 6th Streets. Weather is perfect since I prefer hot summer days
to cold dark winter nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered moving to Austin a few years ago but I nixed the idea since
it is so far from my East Coast roots. I decided instead to visit as often
as possible, but ultimately that just may not be enough for me once I finish
up my fourth trip there. Regardless, it's a great city and there was no
question it would be part of my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="View of Austin, TX" src="../img/austin-tx-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austin has a great tech scene. It's the home of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://sxsw.com/"&gt;South by Southwest&lt;/a&gt; conference in March every year.
Austin is often ranked highly on
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.usatoday.com/tech/columnist/talkingtech/story/2012-08-22/top-tech-startup-cities/57220670/1"&gt;lists of best places to launch a tech start up&lt;/a&gt;
along with San Francisco, Seattle, Boulder, New York, and Boston. The
growth of Dell Computers in the late 80s and 90s helped the city to
establish its silicon credentials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current growing technology companies with an office in Austin include
Facebook, Google, NVidia, Indeed.com, Rackspace, and Zynga. University
of Texas is located in the heart of Austin and is at the forefront of many
areas in computer science and related disciplines. Smaller start ups
include The Daily Dot, Evernote, RightScale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a lot of technology work in Austin. It's the first destination that
people who comment on my trip say &amp;quot;oh, that makes sense if you want to learn
more about technology across the country.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../austin-tx.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather
more information about Austin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/stuseeger/4895843907/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Staying In Shape On The Road</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/staying-in-shape-on-the-road.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-18:staying-in-shape-on-the-road.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I work out almost every day and access to my gym in Arlington is convenient
(a walk across the street). So figuring out how to stay in shape on the road
has been a particular challenge. I don't think I'll have it completely
figured out by the time I leave. It'll probably be something that evolves as
I travel from one city to another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my thoughts outlining the approach I'll take when I start
my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a daily routine that can be done anywhere I'm staying, even if I do not have access to a gym&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rely primarily on bodyweight exercises such as push-ups, sit-ups, body-weight squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring two 30-pound dumbbells, a resistant band, and a jumprope with me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I see a gym nearby where I'm staying, take advantage of it if they have a short-term membership&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example of a daily routine that could be performed anywhere might be
the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Light 15 minute jog to warm up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x supersets of push ups, sit ups, and body weight squats to failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x supersets of 100x jumproping, calf raises holding 2x30 lbs dumbbells, and dumbbell curls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4x dumbbell lunges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3x dumbbell deadlifts to failure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stretching to cool down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main point would be to keep the intensity very high and eliminate resting
periods, similar to a crossfit workout. Intensity is key since I won't
have heavy weight to work with most of the time. Doing these types of
workouts once or twice a day (the second time would be plain running or a
completely different muscle group) should help me to keep in shape while on
the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why New Orleans, Louisiana?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-new-orleans-la.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-18:why-new-orleans-la.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New Orleans has a strong, unique city culture. I previously traveled to
New Orleans in 2010 although I was there for only a few short days. I have
a couple of reasons for returning and making New Orleans the fifth destination
on my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, one of the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.excella.com/"&gt;Excella Consulting&lt;/a&gt; founding
partners, Burton White, is from
New Orleans. He told me about some of the most recent efforts by the state
to create tax breaks for innovative companies to start and come to the area.
I'm interested to see if that type of local government involved has positively
impacted the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I only had a few days to explore the French Quarter during the day
and at night. My experience in the city is really limited. I want to expand
my view of the city into other parts such as St. Charles Ave. The combination
of gaining further insight into the technology of the city plus the
interesting destinations in the area are an appealing mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Aerial view of New Orleans" src="../img/new-orleans-la-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="venture-capital-and-funding"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Venture Capital and Funding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.louisianafund.com/"&gt;The Louisiana Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vcecapital.com/"&gt;BVM Capital&lt;/a&gt;. An office in New Orleans (in addition to their New York office).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.fbtinvestments.com/Venture-Capital.aspx"&gt;FBT Investments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.biz-capital.com/"&gt;Biz Capital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-support"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Support&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://neworleansstartupfund.org/"&gt;New Orleans Startup Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://launchpadnola.com/"&gt;Launchpad New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;. Shared working space in New Orleans.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.startupneworleans.com/"&gt;Start Up New Orleans&lt;/a&gt;. Seems more like a website to spread the word about New Orleans businesses than tangible support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="articles"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Articles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.inc.com/articles/201104/why-new-orleans-is-the-coolest-start-up-city-in-america.html"&gt;Why New Orleans Is the Coolest Start Up City in America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="late-march-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Late March Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm planning to arrive on March 25, so the weather should be fine. I was
previously here in February and the weather was great (high 70s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll &lt;a class="reference external" href="../new-orleans-la.html"&gt;post further notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather more information about New Orleans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/84263554&amp;#64;N00/400064521/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Memphis, Tennessee?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-memphis-tennessee.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-07:why-memphis-tennessee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Several of my DC friends previously lived in Memphis and recommended that
I visit the city while I am travelling through Tennessee. There's great
BBQ, high recommendations for
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.bealestreet.com/wordpress/"&gt;Beale Street&lt;/a&gt;, and a different
Midwestern culture that an East Coast kid like me should find interesting.
Memphis is only three and a half hours from my previous stop in Nashville.
Plus it takes me further Southwest towards my next destination, New Orleans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a combination of convenience and interest combine to make Memphis stop #4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="They take their barbeque seriously in Memphis, TN" src="../img/memphis-tn-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nashville appears to have the most momentum in the state for establishing
a start up scene. But there are some interesting pieces to technology start
ups in Memphis as well. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://startupmemphis.com/"&gt;Start Up Memphis&lt;/a&gt; has
interesting, up to date articles on companies in the area.
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.launchmemphis.com/launchpad/"&gt;Launchpad Memphis&lt;/a&gt; is a coworking
space for start ups and hosts some of the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://mempy.org/"&gt;Memphis Python (MemPy)&lt;/a&gt; meet ups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it's been difficult finding out exactly what start ups are in
Memphis, particularly ones using Python. More digging is necessary in this
area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="venture-capital"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Venture Capital&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.ssmventures.com/"&gt;SSM Ventures&lt;/a&gt;. Wide range of investments
in software companies and healthcare.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mbventures.com/"&gt;MD Venture Partners&lt;/a&gt;. Specific to the life
sciences industry, particularly treatments and cures for musculoskeletal
diseases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="further-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Further Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My further research on Memphis will be posted on the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../memphis-tn.html"&gt;Memphis destination page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/paparutzi/52677265/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Djangonauts.org</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/djangonauts-org.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-09-05:djangonauts-org.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://djangonauts.org/"&gt;djangonauts.org&lt;/a&gt; is a well done centralized
website for Django meetups across the United States. The Chicago Users Group
originally registered the domain name for their own purposes but then
realized it would be of benefit to the greater Django community to have
a centralized location for all users groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out about the website during a lightning talk during DjangoCon 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be using djangonauts.org to contact Django users groups in each city
that I will be visiting in 2013. Hopefully I can meet with most of the groups
on the list.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Living Out of Your Car</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/living-out-of-your-car.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-08-29:living-out-of-your-car.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am not planning to live out of my car while on my five month road trip like
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.quora.com/Would-becoming-homeless-be-a-good-strategy-to-cut-costs-1"&gt;this guy did while bootstrapping his start up&lt;/a&gt;. But his determination
to spend as little money as possible to start his company is impressive
in a weird way. His Quora write up includes a bunch of pictures that show
how he was able to manage such a situation. Inc Magazine even
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.inc.com/magazine/201207/leigh-buchanan/the-leanest-startup-kurt-varner-dailytoaster.html"&gt;wrote an article on his experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guy really thought everything through - or at least fumbled into
a working situation. What I found most interesting is that he did it
out of a Honda Civic and not a minivan like &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://boards.adultswim.com/t5/Babbling/i-am-seriously-considering-living-out-of-a-minivan/td-p/60020874"&gt;some people consider doing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hotels, Airbnb rentals, and friend's residences are the way for me to go.
Particularly since the old S2000's seats don't recline.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Nashville, Tennessee?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-nashville-tn.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-08-19:why-nashville-tn.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have never been to Nashville before, so image I have in my head of what it's
like is a gross generalization of what I am sure it actually is. I mainly
envision country music, a South/Midwestern sort of pride by the people that
reside there, and very little focus on new technology. I am probably wrong
about those three generalizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pleasantly surprised once I began looking into Nashville's venture
capital and start up scene. Nashville intrigues me because no one thinks
about interesting tech and start ups coming out of there, but there seems
to be a lot of momentum behind organizations such as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.startuptn.com/"&gt;Startup Tennessee&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://entrepreneurcenter.com/"&gt;Entrepreneur Center&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://nashville.colabusa.com/"&gt;Colab&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Belle Meade Planation in Nashville, TN" src="../img/nashville-tn-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="first-glance-start-up-scene"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;First Glance Start Up Scene&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a bunch of interesting startups in various industries. Several
examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stratasan.com/"&gt;Stratasan&lt;/a&gt;. Healthcare data analytics. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.stratasan.com/jobs/"&gt;Stratasan is using Python &amp;amp; Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.borderjump.com/"&gt;Borderjump&lt;/a&gt;. International payments and exports API. &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://jobnashville.net/job/16870/lead-developer-platform-architect-nashville-tn-downtownsobro-at/"&gt;Borderjump is using Python &amp;amp; Django&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.sourceyourcity.com/"&gt;Source Your City&lt;/a&gt;. Connects reporters and bloggers with specialty matter experts from various fields. Unclear what technology platform their service is built on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seem to be a cluster of companies in the health care technology space.
I need to do further research to find out why that is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="late-march-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Late March Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm planning to arrive on March 17, so the weather will probably be high 50s
to low 60s. Borderline nice but not warm enough for shorts and flip flops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="more-research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;More Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be &lt;a class="reference external" href="../nashville-tn.html"&gt;posting my research notes&lt;/a&gt; as I continue to gather more information about Nashville, TN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/22711505&amp;#64;N05/6011743607/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>A Few Route Modifications</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/few-route-modifications.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-08-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-08-04:few-route-modifications.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm making a few changes to my planned route (which is now reflected in
the embedded Google Map on the about page). These modifications are due to
conversations I've recently had with several people familiar with these
cities. I decided that based on their recommendations I would be missing out
if I did not visit these destinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I am in the researching and planning phase, it's still easy to make
changes without completely throwing off my entire schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="additions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Orleans, LA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://excella.com/people/burton-white.aspx"&gt;Burton White&lt;/a&gt;, one of the
founding partners at the firm Excella Consulting where I work is originally
from New Orleans. He said that there have been some interesting
developments in the state around small businesses and tech start ups. Plus,
I'm excited to get a chance to have a beer and code in the French
Quarter during a nice day again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bad attempt at visualizing what I'm writing in this post" src="../img/french-quarter-2011.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image: Programming on my old Macbook Air in the French Quarter
back in February 2011.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;San Diego, CA&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother Luke was in San Diego in July and said I definitely need to go
here and at least visit for a couple of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Madison, WI&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several people recommended Madison as a stop that would go well with what
I am looking to do on my trip. I've never been here before but it seems like
an interesting college town that I'd enjoy visiting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="subtractions"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Subtractions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dallas, TX&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The addition of New Orleans took me further South than I originally thought
I would go. Dallas was previously a good stop between Nashville and Austin,
but now it would be out of the way between New Orleans and Austin. Besides,
by removing Dallas I get to spend more time in Austin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Archetypal Days</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/archetypal-days.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-07-28:archetypal-days.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There are several archetypal days I'll have over the course of four
months on the road. Some types of days are more conducive than others
for coding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I need large blocks of time since it's difficult to context switch
while deep diving into difficult problems while programming. Focused
time just won't happen if I only have an hour here, 15 minutes there,
to work. See Paul Graham's essay
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.paulgraham.com/makersschedule.html"&gt;Maker's Schedule, Manager's Schedule&lt;/a&gt; for the clearest explanation of why large blocks of uninterrupted
time are so critical in software development. Some days that won't
be possible, so I'll just keep that in mind as I'm planning what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a list of archetypical days will look like over the course of
my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;8am to 10am.&lt;/em&gt;
Run or workout. Shower, get dressed, have something to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;10am to anywhere from 3pm to 8pm.&lt;/em&gt;
Hit the open road. I've spaced out the driving time between cities to
five to ten hours at most. Ten hours of driving by myself won't be much
fun but it's still manageable within a single day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Late afternoon to evening.&lt;/em&gt;
Arrive at destination. Check in or meet up with a friend. Explore
surroundings to get my bearings. Get to bed early after a long day of
travel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coding days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;7am to 830-9am.&lt;/em&gt;
Run or workout. Shower, get dressed, have something to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;9am through the evening.&lt;/em&gt;
Find a coffee shop, library, cool restaurant, bar (or several of them
to move throughout the day). Code! Eat when hungry. Walk when I need a break or to stretch out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meeting days I plan to break into two chunks - one in the morning, one in
the late afternoon. That way I have two large blocks of time. I can use
one or both chunks to meet with people, code, or explore the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Morning&lt;/em&gt;
Meet up with a start up team, software developer, or someone involved in
a city's local entrepreneurship scene and find out what they're working on
and what makes their city unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Evening&lt;/em&gt;
Same as the morning or use the time for writing blog posts on what I learned
that morning or to do programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tourist days&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;830am to 11am.&lt;/em&gt;
Run or workout. Shower, get dressed, have something to eat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;11am through the evening.&lt;/em&gt;
Explore the city, take pictures, and write blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Causal Attribution</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/causal-attribution.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-07-22:causal-attribution.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of my least favorite quotes is &amp;quot;everything happens for a reason.&amp;quot; The
connotation is clearer if you append &amp;quot;but I didn't plan it out that
way&amp;quot; onto it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Events happen (or &amp;quot;shit happens&amp;quot; if you prefer that expression). It's
easy to ascribe attributes and reasons to those events afterwards.
The human mind works this way naturally. Ascribing reasons to events
after they happen is similar but not exactly the same as
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hindsight"&gt;hindsight bias&lt;/a&gt;, where events
in the past appear more predictable than ones in the future. It appears that
the actual term for explaining past events with reasons is
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Causal_attribution"&gt;causal attribution&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I not like the expression? Because it's giving in to casual
attribution afterwards instead of figuring out what you want ahead of time
and going for it. The expression is demeaning to those who work really hard
to achieve their goals. Those who use that expression are essentially saying,
&amp;quot;I didn't do anything I wanted to do, but that's okay because these other
things happened and I'll just say that's what was supposed to happen to
me all along.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say no thanks to that mentality. If I want something, I'm going to figure
out how to get it and fuel my own relentless drive towards achieving that
objective. When I get it I'm not going to say it was because it was
just supposed to happen. I'm going to say I made it happen. I may have been
helped by other people or fortunate circumstances (in almost all cases
these are true), but I'm not going to discount the effort I put in to have
things work out. The laissez faire attitude of &amp;quot;good things will happen
just because&amp;quot; simply isn't for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's why I'm going to make this trip happen. It's not just going to happen
because it's what is supposed to occur.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Quiet</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/quiet.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-07T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-07-07:quiet.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm writing this post from Kansas City, Missouri. One of the
things I find so striking here is how quiet it is downtown during the day
on weekends. Part of the lack of people may be due to the 100+ degree
weather, but my friend PJ who lives here says this is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compare the quiet here in Kansas City to the constant crowds that are
out at all times of the day in Washington, DC or New York City. I often
have trouble hearing phone conversations while on the main roads when
I walk around Arlington or DC. Here there is a sort of calm settled over
the downtown area until night hits and the bar scene picks up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Downtown Kansas City, MO" src="../img/kansas-city-downtown.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Downtown Kansas City. Pretty quiet until the sun sets.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the explanations for why it is so quiet on the streets is that
there is a very car-centric culture in the Midwest. Actually, most of
America is car-centric with the exception of certain large cities that
have public transportation that works well. Most people just drive
directly to their destinations instead of walking and biking around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another explanation might be that Kansas City is behind the curve with the
trend in reverse urban flight. Perhaps it will take several more years of
revitalization in the downtown area before there are more crowds during
the day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, this is just a quick observation of something I've noticed while
out here that is different from my expectations based on living in East
Coast cities. It'll be interesting to see how the 25-ish cities I'm
visiting next year fit in this pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Breadth Versus Depth</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/breadth-versus-depth.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-07-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-07-04:breadth-versus-depth.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the things I constantly struggle with in my software development
consulting career is balancing breadth versus depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I graduated from &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jmu.edu/"&gt;JMU&lt;/a&gt; in 2005, I was
not deep in anything related to my career. I had a very broad knowledge
of computer science, Java programming, and a few pointers for where I
should look next to learn more. I started working in an enterprise
environment developing software (a really disfunctional environment - but
that's another story) at Freddie Mac. I expanded my breadth in learning
about version control systems, configuration management, handling myself
on a team of developers, and many other real world software development
topics. I became deeper in my knowledge of Java and the Java Virtual
Machine stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I deepened my knowledge of computer science while taking
classes at &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vt.edu/"&gt;Virginia Tech&lt;/a&gt; to earn my Master's degree.
I dove deep into the relatively obscure realm of genetic algorithms and
their application to software testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout my seven year career to date, I've bounced back and forth between
depth and breadth. I made a conscious decision to focus on Python development
once I picked it up in 2007 and ran with it. The tradeoff was a regression
in my depth in the JVM stack (although I still find
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://clojure.org/"&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; very interesting) for a depth in the
Python ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Bad attempt at visualizing what I'm writing in this post" src="../img/breadth-versus-depth.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Above image: A really poor attempt at drawing what I'm writing about in
this post.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This relates to Coding Across America in a direct way because I do struggle
with how long to spend in each city. Certainly if I spent all four months
in Austin, TX, I'd learn a lot about the city, the people who live there,
the local spots to check out, and the technology scene there. I could
inundate myself in Austin's culture. But that wouldn't serve the goal I'm
trying to achieve on my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago when I spent six solid days in Austin, it felt like a
good amount of time to get to know the area. However, I had already been
to Austin for long weekends a couple of times. On the other hand, I did not
exhaustively research where to go in Austin before my trip. So I'm hoping
a combination of research and discussing with people who've lived in cities
before is enough to get me over the learning curve of understanding a
location so that 5-10 days in most cities is enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps that's erring on the side of breadth, but that's the goal. This
isn't a trip about Coding Across Memphis, TN. It's about the United States
as a whole. Better to have more destinations with shorter stints in cities
both large and small rather than a few longer stays in cities that may
skew the results towards a vision that isn't accurate (say, Palo Alto,
Seattle, Austin, and Boulder for instance).&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Charlottesville, Virginia?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-charlottesville-va.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-06-30:why-charlottesville-va.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Originally my first stop was Charlotte, NC. Now it's stop #2. I used to live
in Charlottesville, VA from 2007-09. Charlottesville's distance between DC
and Charlotte makes it a good spot to spend a couple of days before
heading out to new destinations. Charlottesville is one of those small
towns that really grows on you. Given a solid financial situation, I'd
love to have a weekend house here one day that is walking distance to the
Downtown Mall. I'm sure if you polled most University of Virginia
grads they'd say the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting in Charlottesville will give me a couple of days to start my trip
on the right foot. I can talk to some new people, take a lot of pictures,
and make sure I'm really ready to hit the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Charlottesville Downtown Mall looking at the ampitheatre" src="../img/charlottesville-va-2.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /&gt;
&lt;hr class="docutils" /&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlottesville is a small city (~45k residents) and the home of
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.virginia.edu/"&gt;University of Virginia&lt;/a&gt;. Its small size
belies its close knit tech scene. There are a mix of small consulting
firms servicing the local National Ground Intelligence Center (NGIC) and
Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA) market, but also some product-based
companies as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://getopenspace.com/"&gt;Open Space&lt;/a&gt; is a really interesting
collaboration space for individuals and small businesses that need a
place to work. They also host events where speakers will come for an
evening and talk about relevant topics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.darden.virginia.edu/web/batten-institute/"&gt;Batten Institute for Entrepreneurship (Darden School of Business)&lt;/a&gt; studies innovation and
entrepreneurship from an academic standpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://courtsquareventures.com/"&gt;Court Square Ventures&lt;/a&gt; is a venture
capital firm based in Charlottesville. Needs further research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.talloakscapital.com/"&gt;Tall Oaks Capital&lt;/a&gt; is another VC firm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlottesville has quite a few venture capital firms and hedge funds in the
area. I'm guessing this is because many UVA grads do well on Wall Street
then come back to Charlottesville to settle down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="interesting-notes"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interesting Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.hyperink.com/Make-Something-People-Love-Lessons-From-A-Startup-Guy-b1478"&gt;Alexis Ohanian&lt;/a&gt;, a Reddit co-founder, went to UVA and graduated
in 2005.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="coffee-shops"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Coffee Shops&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charlottesville has some great spots to sit and code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.shenandoahjoe.com/"&gt;Shenandoah Joe Coffee Roaster&lt;/a&gt;
on Preston Ave. I've been here before and I love the place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.mudhouse.com/"&gt;Mudhouse&lt;/a&gt; on the Downtown Mall. Again, I've
been to this spot and its location on the Downtown Mall is perfect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.paracoffee.com/"&gt;Para Coffee&lt;/a&gt; on The Corner (near Grounds).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://latazacoffeehouse.com/"&gt;Lataza Coffee House&lt;/a&gt; in Belmont.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.greenberrys.com/locations.php"&gt;Greenberry's&lt;/a&gt; - a chain, but
I really like their location at Barrack's Road Shopping Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="march-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;March Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;March weather in Charlottesville is generally cold, but it varies from
day-to-day. I may have to be careful driving or change some plans if any
snow hits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="photo-attribution"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Photo Attribution&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/small_realm/6370977289/"&gt;Flickr Creative Commons License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Camera</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/camera.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-06-24:camera.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I knew I needed a better camera than the one in my Droid 3 for this trip.
At first I thought about digital SLRs, but the additional size, weight,
and complexity turned me off to them. I am not currently interested
enough in learning the intricate details of tuning a camera or changing a
lens to take the perfect picture. It is unlikely I would gain
any benefit from an SLR over a quality point-and-shoot camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some basic web research, I settled on the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B006UMM1PO/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=minimneeds-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B006UMM1PO"&gt;Canon PowerShot ELPH 110 HS&lt;/a&gt; and a
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004XIB9T6/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=minimneeds-20&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B004XIB9T6"&gt;Transcend 64 GB SDXC Flash Memory Card&lt;/a&gt;. The camera got great reviews and the
memory card should have plenty of space for all the pictures I take. I'm
looking forward to using a real camera to post pictures of the people and
places in every city I stay in.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Projects</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/projects.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-06-18:projects.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Since coding is in the title of this site and my trip across the country,
what will I be programming? Part of my excitement with the trip is having
focused, dedicated blocks of time to sit in coffee shops or restaurants
and work on projects I'm passionate about launching. While my development
projects often shift every six months to a year, I'm sure I'll be working
on some of all of the projects listed below in some capacity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. ProofDriven&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2012, I launched a web application where developers can go to
create custom financial reports to show that technology upgrades are
important investments for companies to make. The first design was... awful.
But, I launched! The new design is way better, despite the fact that I
designed it all myself instead of using a template. I give credit for the
aesthetic improvement to Bootstrapping Design and several design books
I read between the launches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I plan to improve the way the site works and add new financial reports
that show how new specific technologies and processes provide a positive
return on investment. In addition, I will write blog posts on how
developers can encourage technical improvements in their work environments
even when their organization is technologically risk-adverse. Sure, it's
not the sexiest stuff, but it's important for helping drive improvements
in the way thousands of organizations across the country work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. My &amp;quot;Idea-Launch-Marketing-Iterate&amp;quot; Personal Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've found I unfortunately write a lot of boilerplate code and spend time
figuring some of the same things out each time I launch a personal project.
I'm trying to automate some of those boilerplate pieces with a centralized
web application that allows me to come up with ideas, launch and
automatically scale them with Linode/AWS/Heroku, then market the app, collect
and show metrics with statsd and Graphite, then iterate on promising ideas.
This project is still coming together but so far I like how it's going
and its potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Excella Connect - Contact Management and Data Analysis for Excella&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently created a web application for Excella Consulting to better
understand our connections to different companies and industries. At first
I used LinkedIn data, but unfortunately LinkedIn imposes archaic and
shortsighted restrictions on the terms of use for their API. LinkedIn
just &lt;em&gt;doesn't get&lt;/em&gt; how APIs should work to make them useful to third
parties. Someone is going to eventually disrupt their business by getting
things right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, if the forthcoming pilot initiative within Excella is
successful, I'll probably spend time developing functionality for the
product that will allow visualizations and data access to other internal
applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Potential Client Web Apps I Can Develop Remotely&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a new or existing client is looking for someone to develop a Python/Django
app, I'd consider spending up to 20 hours a week working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned above, it's likely these projects will change and new ones
will get added, but right now that's what I think of with the &amp;quot;Coding&amp;quot; part
of Coding Across America.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>The Conversations</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/the-conversations.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-06-17:the-conversations.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By far my favorite part of planning and undertaking this trip is talking
to people I've just met about where they've lived and where I should go.
When you ask people where they are from and where they've visited
the responses are often surprising. Asking detailed questions
about where they recommend going if you only have a few days in
town not only brings out useful responses, it's also a small window on that
person's life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people love sports - they'll tell you to check out their baseball
stadium or tailgate at a football game. Other people love the outdoors -
they'll say go hiking at a nearby national park. I love checking out
independent coffee shops to code (surprise!), read a book, or catch up
with a friend. Other people have eclectic interests that you would never
otherwise be exposed to if you hadn't taken the time to ask them what
to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while I'm spending much of my time on coding and technology
during this trip, I know there's going to be many random tangents and
paths that I'll go down. I can't foresee those paths now, but
keeping an open mind about new ideas and activities is a big part of the
journey.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Estimating A Budget</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/estimating-budget.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-11T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-06-11:estimating-budget.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Until I plan my exact trip route, book places to stay, and figure out what
(if any) tech conferences I'm going to, it will be hard to determine an
exact budget for my trip. However, I can create a ballpark figure based
on averaging an aggressive budget and a conservative budget. &amp;quot;Conservative&amp;quot;
in this case means I try to spend as little money as possible while
in the aggressive estimation I do not worry about most of what I'm
paying throughout my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General expenses to estimate include (in rough order of magnitude):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accomodations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas &amp;amp; Car Maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food &amp;amp; Beverages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc (parking, tolls, cell phone w/ data plan costs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="conservative"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conservative&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this is the most conservative estimate if I plan to spend as little
money as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accomodations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's average about $75 a night for rooms. Some cities will obviously be
much more expensive than others. I'll also have to stay outside the main
areas of most cities to get a decent rate or watch for particularly good
deals on Airbnb. Couch surfing is also an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;120 nights * 75 = $9000&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$9000 actually isn't too bad considering I would pay about $7000 for my
rent &amp;amp; utilities from mid-March through the end of July anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas &amp;amp; Car Maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming I go about 9000 miles, I get 20 MPG (I get worse gas mileage with
the top down), and gas hovers around $5 a gallon (I need premium fuel for
the S2000), I'll spend about $2250. Add another $250 for oil changes and
other random things adds up to $2500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food &amp;amp; Beverages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This one seems the most difficult to estimate because it really depends on
how much I eat out while traveling. Obviously I won't have access to a
kitchen most of the time. But I usually eat a lot of raw fruit and nuts
anyway, so I don't see this as much of an issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will still have to eat out when I want a regular meal, but for the most
part I'll shop at grocery stores I find along the way. Let's say I eat out
half the time (~60 nights), spend $40 on average throughout breakfast, lunch,
and dinner (sometimes way higher, other times way lower), that comes out
to 60*40 = $2400. Round up to $2500 just to make it even with gas &amp;amp; car
maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yikes, this is the most difficult one to estimate. My cell phone plan with
a data connection (including wifi hotspot) costs $120 a month. parking
depends on where I stay and what places I visit. Tolls depend on what roads
I take. I'll punt and say $500 a month, so about $2000 additional throughout
my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservative total: $9000 + 2500 + 2500 + 2000 = $16000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems low to me but perhaps I'm just really used to Washington, DC
prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="aggressive"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Aggressive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a reasonably aggressive estimate. I'm not looking to stay at the Ritz
every night but in some cities it's worth staying in a nice hotel if it
has a great location.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accomodations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bump from $75 average per night to $125 average per night and we're at
120 * 125 = $15000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="2"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas &amp;amp; Car Maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this estimate has the least variability in it unless something
really bad happens to my car. Let's add $3000 in case I have a bad
breakdown plus I spend more money on gas than I estimated in the conservative
case. $2500 plus $3000 for aggressive estimate is $5500 total.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="3"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Food &amp;amp; Beverages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll double this to $5000 from $2500.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple" start="4"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Misc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Increase by 150% to $5000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aggressive total: $16000 + 5500 + 5000 + 5000 = $31500. This seems high to
me but not out of the realm of possibility if I'm not careful about what I
spend while on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="summary"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So those are some spitball figures I threw out. I'm estimating about $16k
to $32k cost total for the trip including accomodations, food &amp;amp; drinks,
car-related expenses, and other miscellaneous charges. I'll refine the
estimates as my plans become more concrete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Jump Forward One Year</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/jump-forward-one-year.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-06-05:jump-forward-one-year.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently remarked to someone I was talking to about my trip that it is
odd knowing I will not be in Washington, DC at this same time next year.
I've lived in Virginia for the past eleven years (4 &amp;#64; JMU, 2 in Arlington,
2 1/2 in Charlottesville, 2 1/2 back in Arlington). It's easy to fall into
a trap of taking things for granted when you know you always have them at
your disposal. For instance, I don't check out the national monuments at
all except when I have family or friends visiting from out of town. It's
easy to get caught up in thinking that you can do that sort of thing
whenever. Whenever often turns into never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's important to know that you will not have forever to experience the
particular advantages of your location. Knowing your time is limited
forces you to enjoy the things around you that you know you'll miss once you're far off. Jumping
forward one year and knowing that I will likely be in Seattle at that time
allows me to realize how limited the remainder of my time here will be. Of
course I'm planning to come back to DC after my trip, but who knows where
life takes me once I'm traveling across the country. Better to use
limited time I have here and truly enjoy DC rather than continue to
in some ways waste the great parts of this city by not taking advantage of
its unique aspects that I won't get anywhere else in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why Charlotte, North Carolina?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-charlotte-nc.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-31T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-05-31:why-charlotte-nc.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Charlotte, North Carolina is the first destination on my trip outside of
Washington, DC. Charlotte is approximately 400 miles from DC (about 7 hours)
and several people I know have moved to Charlotte to escape the
government-centric DC area for careers focused on commercial business.
Charlotte is also the largest city in North Carolina, and the second largest
banking center in the US. This is a summary of my pre-research reasons
for why I'm traveling to Charlotte.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="reality-check"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reality Check&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://news.ycombinator.com/"&gt;Hacker News&lt;/a&gt; which biases
my opinions towards small start ups and against large firms. Charlotte may
provide a grounding in what many US cities consider technology to be useful
for. Tech can be a support function for an industries that were around long
before the term &amp;quot;computer&amp;quot; was used to describe a machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="start-up-culture"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Up Culture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am unaware in my limited knowledge of any start up companies coming out
of North Carolina. Is there a culture there that support risk-taking? If
you try to start a venture or join a small company that fails, is there a
stigma attached to that failure?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="the-financial-industry"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Financial Industry&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It appears that the financial industry heavily impacts the tech culture in
Charlotte. Financial institutions are notoriously large, bureaucratic
organizations with many policies, procedures, and controls in place designed
(but not always successful) for protecting customers' investments. How does
that impact the tech scene in Charlotte, NC?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="march-weather"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;March Weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weather in mid-March is a secondary consideration since Charlotte is
my first destination. I plan to reach Charlotte by late in the day on
March 12, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="research"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Research&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My further research on Charlotte will be posted on the
&lt;a class="reference external" href="../charlotte-nc.html"&gt;Charlotte destination page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Possessions</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/possessions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-05-28:possessions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many wealthy people are little more than the janitors of their possessions.
- Frank Lloyd Wright&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several years ago I decided see if I could eventually
fit all my possessions in &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Honda_S2000"&gt;my car&lt;/a&gt;.
Until recently, this goal seemed like an impossible task. Look at how small that
trunk is. The car has no back seat! I also had quite the volume of stuff: couches,
a desktop computer, hundreds of books, a bed, a desk, and a
closet full of clothes. But I've slowly pared down my possessions after moving
nine times in the last seven years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I leave in March, I will get rid of the last two pieces of furniture I
own: a bed and a desk. Both are on their last legs so I am not concerned with
giving them away or trashing them. I read and gave away most of my books (I have
about three dozen currently that I'm still going through) and now I only buy
books on the Kindle or through &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.oreilly.com/"&gt;O'Reilly&lt;/a&gt;. I use
a Macbook Pro laptop instead of a desktop computer. Slowly but surely the
shift from having lots of &amp;quot;stuff&amp;quot; to a more focused set of useful possessions
is happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A burden is removed when you stop thinking about buying things and
shift into a mindset of only keeping what you need. Combine that mindset with a
redoubled focus on the people around you and the experiences you
share together. This perspective shift may not be for everyone - materialism
is still a big part of the American lifestyle. But reducing possessions and
thinking more about those around you is worth a thought while we are in the
shadow of the &amp;quot;Great Recession&amp;quot; and most people are already forced to cut back.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Contributions</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/contributions.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-05-26:contributions.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Coding Across America
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/contributors.html"&gt;contributors page&lt;/a&gt;
is a list of everyone that has in some way given me advice, recommendations,
or in some way shaped my trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four month journey I am starting in March is much too large to have
planned and figured out just by myself. I want to recognize everyone from
behind the scenes that make the trip happen. In addition, just having
a list of names isn't interesting nor does it do justice to the people who've
taken the time to help me out. Therefore every name has a link to something
amazing that person has done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Ryan Anderson, who I graduated with from JMU in 2005, took a picture
that became the cover of Science magazine in December 2010. That's an amazing
accomplishment. I hope that going through the list of contributors is a
fascinating look into the lives of people who helped make Coding Across America
possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>What To Do In Each City</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/what-to-do-in-each-city.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-05-24:what-to-do-in-each-city.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Here are the main places and events I intend to visit while on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Meet ups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been to a bunch of great meet ups in the Washington, DC area. I am
sure many of the destinations on the list also have great meet ups. I'll
lean heavily towards areas that I work in, such as Python, web development,
mobile development, and DevOps. However, if I see something that fits well
in my schedule I would not mind attending a Ruby on Rails, node.js, or
similar event.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Conferences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conferences get expensive quickly and they generally last several days, so
I will have to be careful with this one. But I'm keeping up with where
conferences will be next year through &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.lanyrd.com/"&gt;Lanyrd&lt;/a&gt;.
It's possible something will line up perfectly with a stop in a city that
I'm planning to stay more than 3-4 days in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Start Ups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm looking to meet with developers and founders of start ups to find out
more about what they like and don't like about their location. By
bringing attention to common problems start ups face in all cities
and understanding the difficulties of particular locations, perhaps we can
gave insight into how we can improve our situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Coffee Shops&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll be doing a lot of my own coding while on the road. I'm very
comfortable doing work in coffee shops. I look forward to checking
out the best spots in every city both large and small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Tourist Spots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a road trip so I will be taking pictures and checking out
interesting landmarks and &amp;quot;touristy&amp;quot; spots along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more spots I intend to check out in various cities, but that
covers the majority of what I'm generically looking for in each destination.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Goals</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/goals.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-05-22:goals.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It is important to focus on specific goals when undertaking any large
project. I consider four months away from work to travel a major project,
so here are my initial thoughts on what my goals are for Coding Across
America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Gain a greater understanding of tech culture across the United States&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is only so much you can learn about other locations by reading about
them. Sometimes you have to experience things for yourself. I'm working
to combine three methods of learning to gain a better understanding of
tech culture in the US. First, through reading and research from articles and
blog posts on the Internet. Second, by visiting each city, exploring its
locations and talking to people who live there. Third, by synthesizing and
writing about my research and experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the reading and writing will take place before I begin the trip in
March 2013. That way I can have an understanding of where I am going and
attempt to spend my time as efficiently as possible in each destination. I
may not get everything right, but it should yield better results than just
&amp;quot;going for it&amp;quot; without thinking through what I want to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Coding&amp;quot; is the first word in the title of this project for a reason. I'm
not traveling the country just to see the sights. I want to take a lot of
the free time I have and develop software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Bring my experiences back to Washington, DC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that while there is a pervasive negative attitude towards
the work that goes on in Washington, DC that things can get better. I found
myself spiraling towards cynicism after a few difficult government consulting
stints. However, my experiences at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau
have led me to understand that government can truly serve the American
public in an open, honest, and efficient way. No agency is perfect, but from
what I've seen if the attitude of employees and consultants at CFPB could
be brought to bear on other parts of the government it would profoundly
improve how operations are run. More on this in a later post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does this have to do with Coding Across America? If I've found positive
potential through my experiences in DC, I firmly believe I can find further
knowledge in other parts of the US. That's the hypothesis anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are my high-level goals for Coding Across America. Each one may on the
surface appear independent, but they are intertwined. The world is now
being shaped by software and if we are to have a well run functioning
government, we need to be better at developing our ideas of how to
put ideas into code. Gaining a greater understanding of tech culture
across the US and spending time talking to people in cities both large and
small will help to shape my ideas around the subject so I can hopefully
spread those positive ideas when I return to our nation's capital.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>Why?</title><link href="http://www.codingacrossamerica.com/why-coding-across-america.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Matt Makai</name></author><id>tag:www.codingacrossamerica.com,2012-05-21:why-coding-across-america.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Why travel across the United States for four months? There's a few ways to
approach this question, so I'll answer three variations separately then
bring it back together at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Why travel at all?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have lived in Virginia for the past ten years and New Jersey for the
previous eighteen since I was born. I do not consider myself
well-traveled even within the US. Most of my traveling has been to
visit friends on the East Coast. With the exception of a few excursions
to Austin, TX and Seattle, WA, I have not seen many places outside of
the mid-Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does that matter? Maybe, maybe not, but I want to find out. I've spent the
better part of my 20s earning &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.jmu.edu/"&gt;degrees&lt;/a&gt; from
&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.vt.edu/"&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://www.virginia.edu/"&gt;universities&lt;/a&gt;
which has helped me learn a lot and grow as a person, but I do wonder if
I'm missing a different perspective on life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Why travel across the US and not the entire world?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there's a lot of value in traveling the world and seeing different
cultures. I also think that concentrating my time in the US will allow me
to focus more on technology culture here. I know many other countries have
interesting tech scenes, particularly in Europe and parts of Asia, but
I'm not as tied into those parts of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a more mundane level, I want to drive my car across the country. Staying
in the US also cuts down on logistics such as passports, cell phone
connections, and exchanging currency. Staying within the 50 states is just
&lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt; in a lot of ways. I prefer spending my time focusing on technology,
coding, and talking to people within the US for this trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Why travel for three to four months?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm sure I could fly through several cities over a few weeks or spend an even
longer amount of time traveling. I think though that three to four months
is the sweet spot between feeling pressured to go-go-go and feeling like I
have too much time on my hands in every city. Moderate constraints often
produce better results than unhinged projects. On the other hand, too many
constraints, such as a very short schedule, wouldn't allow me to accomplish
what I'm looking to do on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wrap up&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why four months? I need to get away from Washington, DC for awhile and gain
greater perspective on tech culture across the United States. Staying in
the United States cuts down on logistical issues and allows me to focus
on our tech culture. Four months provides a solid block of time to travel
to many cities and explore each one in unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry></feed>